<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Static Site in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a summer barbecue, a friend asked if I could build a website for his new restaurant. But what he didn&#39;t know was that I haven&#39;t built a static site in nearly a decade. However I couldn&#39;t let him spend thousands of dollars on a cookie cutter website designed by a firm that knew nothing about his restaurant.
We started coming up with ideas right away over a couple of beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Job Isn&#39;t Writing Code</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</guid>
      <description>Every line of code you write is a liability. That line of code you just wrote adds complexity to your code base, gives you more nuances to remember, it might even be a bug. If code is so expensive and dangerous. What can you do? After all, you are a developer.
The answer: You must remember your real job&amp;hellip; Delivering value to the users.
Users don&amp;rsquo;t care what your class hierarchy looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lodash Worked Itself Out of a Job</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</guid>
      <description>I really loved lodash. It brough the joy of compact functional code to JavaScript. Especially 6 years ago when I first embraced it. It was a wonderful library. Back then, there was no ES6, no Babel, and terrible browser incompatabilities ran rampant. Lodash along with jQuery were the saving light of that time.
I gravitated towards using Lodash because the first language I learned was Scheme. It had functional programing at it&amp;rsquo;s core, and highly influanced how I think about code to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>