<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes - Day 5</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day5/</guid>
      <description>Insist on Using Objective Criteria Don&amp;rsquo;t take offers at face value. Try to figure out the objective reasoning behind the offer. Just asking about the reasoning makes the other person evaluate their position. Once they are in an evaluation mode, it opens up the floor for you to present your reasoning.
With all the reasoning is on the table, insist on a fair process. Be ready to compromise between two equally worthy criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day4/</guid>
      <description>Invent Options for Mutual Gain You can&amp;rsquo;t settle on a good outcome without having the right ideas. Separate your brainstorming from the decision process. Ban judgment and throw out the craziest ideas you can. Then use those ideas as launchpads for refinement.
Try to understand why everyone came up with different ideas. Use these differences in values, believes, and interests to settle on an outcome. You can&amp;rsquo;t reach an agreement without differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day3/</guid>
      <description>Focus on Interest not Positions Negotiations start because both parties have an interest. They use their interests to develop a position. Conflict arises because each parties sees their position as the only way to succeed. And bot parties end up upset with each other or losing out on a lot of what they wanted.
That entire situation can be avoided. Don&amp;rsquo;t come up with your position before you talk to the other person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day2/</guid>
      <description>Separate the people from the problem It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to address the problem objectively. Every negotiation also involves people. With people come people problems that are separate from the main issue at hand.
First off you need to understand the other parties perspective. They might not see things the same way. They might hold biases. Or they might feel like they didn&amp;rsquo;t get to participate in the process and are getting a solution force onto them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Yes - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/getting-to-yes/day1/</guid>
      <description>The problem We negotiate every day. Everything from a pay raise, to what to have for dinner is a negotiation. The only thing that changes is the stakes.
We generally view negotiations as having two outcomes. Either we give something up or we win by making the other person give something up. This is a sad zero sum view of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s the view of if there is a winner there must be a loser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 14</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day14/</guid>
      <description>The end The greatest reward the divers received was letting the families know that someone still cared about their dead husbands, brothers, and friends. There was no amount of money or publicity that could be greater than that.
After all, we are made for each other. What greater purpose could you have than helping fellow man? Marcus Aurelius put it best. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s good for the bee is good for the whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 13</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day13/</guid>
      <description>The U-Boat is Our Moment Kohler and Chatterton lost their families because of the obsession with the u-boat. It might have worked out for Kohler, but Chatterton is getting dangerously close to sacrificing everything for this wreck.
Many people that accomplished great things let themselves become consumed by an idea. But it&amp;rsquo;s not the only way. You can approach problems with moderation and longevity. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find a solution to the problem after giving it your all, move on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 12</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day12/</guid>
      <description>None of us is coming back The command and first officer couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more different in their leadership style.
The commander treated every situation with the utmost professionalism. He won the man&amp;rsquo;s trust through his discipline.
The first officer was the complete opposite. He was friendly and open with the men. The whole crew became his friends. They laughed and joked around every time they were off duty.
Despite these differences, they both respected each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 11</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day11/</guid>
      <description>A missed signal Chatterton tried a new strategy for exploring the u-boat. Instead of rummaging through the debris, he stopped and calmly absorbed his surrounding. Allowing himself to notice more than he had before.
Taking it slow , especially with tough problem, can be seem counter productive. You want to start resolving the problem right away. However, there is a better strategy. If you take a step back and allow yourself room to process, you gain insight you previously wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 10</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day10/</guid>
      <description>History Mauled Chatterton and Kohler finally found the identity of the sub. To achieve this, they had to go against historical books. They read the actual communications and proved even the experts wrong.
As said by Mark Twain: &amp;ldquo;Whenever you find yourself on the side of the majority, it is time to pause and reflect.&amp;rdquo; Question the common wisdom if things don&amp;rsquo;t line up. History books have been rewritten. Scientists actively work to prove each other wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 9</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day9/</guid>
      <description>A Heavy Toll Chatterton and Kohler were becoming frustrated. They performed numerous dives but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a scrap of identification. The one place they didn&amp;rsquo;t check were the well preserved human remains.
Despite the allure of easy information, they quickly decided against it. Not because someone would find out. They were at 230 feet with no one else round. They would touch the remains out of pure respect for the soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 8</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day8/</guid>
      <description>Nothing at That Location Chatterton approaches research and diving the same way. He gets the big picture first. Scanning at the highest and safest level. Building a game plan and gathering valuable information.
Once he finds something promising, he dives in as deep as possible. Gleaning everything he can from the best opportunity the situation presents to him.
This is a great way to approach your problem. Spend some time upfront making sure you are tackling the right problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 7</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day7/</guid>
      <description>Horenburg&amp;rsquo;s Knife Nagel and Chatterton tried to keep the u-boat a secret and do research on their own. But they could only get so far on the on their own.
When they caved and put out a press release about their discovery, they got more information in a week than in months of research. Others got excited about the discovery, they had a passion for u-boats, or lived during the period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 6</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day6/</guid>
      <description>Richie Kohler A man built on self education and strong work ethic. He gets genuinely excited about shipwreck diving and the artifacts he can find.
We all enjoy an activity because we find pleasure in the little things about that activity. Often people enjoy different aspects. Chatterton enjoys the story of the submarines while Kohler enjoys the artifacts he can find. This difference made Chatterton misjudged Kohler for a bad guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 5</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day5/</guid>
      <description>Crazy Deep The divers forgot their limit on a deep dive. They became caught up in the excitement and push further than they ever have.
It can be healthy to push yourself, but you need to know your limits. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be too uncomfortable in a situation. Neither do you want to repeatedly push yourself further than you have gone before.
Feldman learned this lesson the hard way by going on the deepest dive he&amp;rsquo;s ever attempted two times in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day4/</guid>
      <description>John Chatterton A man on an endless quest of self exploration. John Chatterton didn&amp;rsquo;t follow other advice. Instead, he followed his own path. He chose to get answers through experience in the army, volunteering for Vietnam, and becoming a commercial diver.
In all his endeavors, he gave everything and learned every detail. An attitude like this lead to him becomes great at his vocation.
Taking on the tasks no one likes, giving everything to every job, and learning the smallest detail are the values of a great professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day3/</guid>
      <description>A Shape of Power The divers were ecstatic to find a mysterious u-boat where no u-boat should have been. They dove in ready to take full advantage of they 25 minutes they had to look at the submarine. Everyone explored a different part and grew more excited with each new discovery.
Once the expedition was over, everyone handled the secret of the u-boat differently. Some dove into research, some couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist telling a friend, and others visited submarines at a museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day2/</guid>
      <description>Zero Viz Shipwreck divers face countless dangers. When going down they could lose the line, get caught up in a current, or become intoxicated by nitrogen. Inside the wreck, they can easily get lost or snagged on debris. And on the way up they can suffer permanent injury or death from the bends.
They only have one prevention for all these troubles. Staying calm and solving their problems one at time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Divers - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/shadow-divers/day1/</guid>
      <description>The Book of Number Sailors hold their most secret spots in a book of numbers. Some use these numbers as their lively hood by taking others there for fishing. Others do it for the thrill of exploring the unknown. They love the exploration and aren&amp;rsquo;t concerned if it&amp;rsquo;s a great wreck or a literal pile of garbage.
This passion echoes across disciplines. No matter the vocation, there are those that enjoy every minute of what they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 5</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day5/</guid>
      <description>The small choices you make today determine the future  &amp;ldquo;When you deal with people who have trouble, you can either choose to take the token that says &amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s no big deal&amp;rsquo; or the token that says &amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world.&amp;rsquo; Whichever token you pick, they&amp;rsquo;ll take the other.&amp;rdquo;
 Your company culture, your mood, even your level of stress are all determined by the small choices you make every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day4/</guid>
      <description>Question the norm and default to no  &amp;ldquo;Culture is what culture does.&amp;rdquo;
 Don&amp;rsquo;t base your culture on best practices. In fact, don&amp;rsquo;t base anything on best practices alone. Only use these practices as a starting point. Strive to push things forward and create something better than the status quo.
To become better than the norm, you need focus. The only way to gain focus is to say no to all the unnecessary things you are saying yes to right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day3/</guid>
      <description>You work with people  &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to fall for someone&amp;rsquo;s carefully crafted story.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to fall for someone&amp;rsquo;s carefully crafted story.&amp;rdquo;
When hiring or just working with someone, get to know them as a person. Everyone has families, hobbies, and worries. Get to know these things, about the people you spend 40 hours a week with. It leads to a better work environment and make sharing ideas easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day2/</guid>
      <description>Your words carry more power than you think  &amp;ldquo;1 percent occasions like that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t drive policy 99 percent of the time.&amp;rdquo;
 Chances are, you have someone looking up to you or you are an officially a leader. This comes with great responsibility.
Be careful with the example that you set and what you give you attention to. Staying up late, responding to emails on the weekends, and looking at thing &amp;ldquo;just in case&amp;rdquo; all serve to create a bad culture around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day1/</guid>
      <description>Calm is the Secret to Great Work  &amp;ldquo;Comparison is the death of joy.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Mark Twain
 Drawn out goals, packed schedules, and crazy work environments sap the calm from any workspace.
Remember that packing your schedule and trying to get more done is not the way to stay creative. Instead allow yourself uninterrupted chunks of time, at least 90 minutes to work. Use this time to to accomplish what you need to and produce something of quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Static Site in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a summer barbecue, a friend asked if I could build a website for his new restaurant. But what he didn&#39;t know was that I haven&#39;t built a static site in nearly a decade. However I couldn&#39;t let him spend thousands of dollars on a cookie cutter website designed by a firm that knew nothing about his restaurant.
We started coming up with ideas right away over a couple of beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Job Isn&#39;t Writing Code</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</guid>
      <description>Every line of code you write is a liability. That line of code you just wrote adds complexity to your code base, gives you more nuances to remember, it might even be a bug. If code is so expensive and dangerous. What can you do? After all, you are a developer.
The answer: You must remember your real job&amp;hellip; Delivering value to the users.
Users don&amp;rsquo;t care what your class hierarchy looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universally Testable Dependencies in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript dependencies are notoriously hard to mock and test across framework and environments. However, Dependency Injection (DI) ensures testability. It is common in statically typed languages, like Java or Go, but is also useful in dynamic languages like JavaScript.
This article will guide you through a simple technique that can apply to any JavaScript code base, frontend or backend, independent of frameworks and libraries.
The technique I am going to demonstrate is arguably not true DI, since the dependencies are still managed by the module using them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript Setup for Leiningen Project With Emacs</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</guid>
      <description>A good development environment if fundamental to being productive. This is especially true for Lisps. A good environment can greatly speed up your development process and allow you to utilize the full power of Clojure or any other Lisp.
This tutorial is focused on a ClojureScript environment for a Leiningen based project being developed in Emacs.
Why Emacs? Emacs has a great setup for most programming languages but really shines when it comes to Lisps, including Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lodash Worked Itself Out of a Job</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</guid>
      <description>I really loved lodash. It brough the joy of compact functional code to JavaScript. Especially 6 years ago when I first embraced it. It was a wonderful library. Back then, there was no ES6, no Babel, and terrible browser incompatabilities ran rampant. Lodash along with jQuery were the saving light of that time.
I gravitated towards using Lodash because the first language I learned was Scheme. It had functional programing at it&amp;rsquo;s core, and highly influanced how I think about code to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient CSV Imports in Rails</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rails-csv-imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rails-csv-imports/</guid>
      <description>Rails has great capabilities for working CSV files. However, like with many things, the most obvious way is not the most efficient.
We noticed this when our server had major fluctuations in memory consumption. After digging through metrics, made easy thanks to Prometheus and Grafana. We noticed that the spikes were due to our CSV uploads.
Examining CSV Import Our processor is responsible for bringing in coordinates from legacy systems and ones that cannot support our API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix talk</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/phoenix-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/phoenix-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a talk, at the local Fullstack Meetup, on the Phoenix Framework. Phoenix is the de facto web framework for Elixir.
In this talk, I cover some of the best features of Phoenix:
 Erlang: The platmor which Elixir and Phoenix are build on. (albeit very brief overview of the major features) Plug: The specification for composable module design that gives Phoenix much of it&amp;rsquo;s power. Ecto: The database integration layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Universal Haskell Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universal-haskell-dev-enviornment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universal-haskell-dev-enviornment/</guid>
      <description>Haskell is notoriously difficult to setup, which probably led to many people being scared away from ever getting started. However, there has been a lot of work done to address these short comings. And there is a way to setup a very pleasant environment thanks to the hard work of many projects.
Traditional methods included:
 Installing The Haskell Platform, which was a great project in it&amp;rsquo;s time but always seems to lag a few GHC versions behind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>